Smith Brothers Records
Smith Brothers Records
1908-1964
Smith Brothers (Poughkeepsie, N.Y.)
6 linear ft.
Records of the cough drop company founded in 1847 in Poughkeepsie, New York. Collection includes minute books (1922-1964), stock records (1920-1964), and executive reports (1919-1957).
148670
Biographical History
Smith Brothers Cough Drop Company was founded in Poughkeepsie, New York in 1847 by brothers William Wallace Smith (1830-1913) and Andrew Smith (1836-1895). Their father, James Smith, had emigrated from Scotland and settled in New York, where he started a small candy business. Upon purchasing the formula for a "cough candy" from a traveling man, James added the items to his product line. Menthol cough drops were added in 1922, a cough syrup in 1926, and the wild cherry flavor, the firm's most popular and best known, in 1948. The business continued to be owned and operated by the Smith family until 1963 when it merged with Warner-Lambert (a subsidiary of Pfizer Corp.); as of 1964 the Smith Brothers Cough Drop line was acquired by F & F Foods of Chicago, who continues to manufacture it today (2010).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Smith Brothers Records consist of minute books, legal material, financial material, stock books, executive reports, sales books, and general records. The bulk of the material is in bound volumes.
Arrangement of the Collection
The material remains in original order, as received.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; New York State; Smith, W. Wallace (William Wallace), 1900-1989.; Smith, Andrew, 1836-1895.; Smith Brothers (Poughkeepsie, N.Y.) -- Archives.; Candy industry -- United States.; Pharmaceutical industry -- United States.; Poughkeepsie (N.Y.) -- Industries.; Minute books.; Reports.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Smith Brothers Division of Warner-Lambert Pharmaceutical Co., 1966.
Inventory
- Corporate records
  - Minute books, 1922-1964; 7 volumes
  - Bylaws, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Original bylaws (Box 1)
  - Certificate of amendment, 5 Jan 1953 (Box 1)
  - Legal correspondence and documents, 5 Jan 1953; 1 box
  - Stock books, 21 volumes
  - Executive reports, 1919-1939; 1942-1944,; 1946-1957; 13 volumes
  - Consolidated sheets, 1951-1961; 3 volumes
  - Ledgers, expense, 1956-1957; 1 volume
  - Ledgers, inventory, 3 volumes
  - Bank statements, 1 volume
  - Accounts payable, 1 volume
  - Sales brokers, 1916-1917; 6 volumes
  - Sales analysis, 1908-1958; 4 volumes
  - General records, 1918-1934; cash received, cash analysis; 7 volumes
  - Cash received registers, 1934-1956; 13 volumes
  - California, sales analysis, 1952-1964; 3 volumes
  - California, detailed distribution, 1962-1964; 1 volume
  - Restaurant, accounts payable index, 1915; 1 volume
  - Restaurant, invoices supporting fixed capital charges, 1915; 1 volume
  - Delaware corporation, account distribution, 1962-1964; 1 volume
  - Accounts receivable and payable, 1917-1926; 1 volume
  - Recipes, 1 envelope
  - Corporate seals, 4 items